paymaster24.com 2018-08-20

# Paymaster24 Privacy Policy 1. Introduction

Paymaster24 Privacy Policy
1. Introduction
Paymaster24 Ltd is a company incorporated in England and Wales (company number
08387550) whose registered head office is 7 Portugal Place, Cambridge, CB5 8AF,
England, UK. Paymaster24 Ltd is an Authorised Payment Institution by the FCA
(Financial Conduct Authority) in the United Kingdom under the Payment Services
Regulations 2009 for the provision of payment services with the relevant permissions to
operate within the EEA (European Economic Area). FCA registration number: 599682.
In this Privacy Policy Data Protection Legislation "means the EU General Data Protection
Regulation 2016/679, together with all other applicable legislation relating to privacy or
data protection, and where we use the terms "personal data", "data subject",
"controller", “processor” and "process" (and its derivatives), such terms shall have the
meanings given to them in the Data Protection Legislation.
This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”), which includes our Cookie Policy, sets out the
basis on which Paymaster24 Ltd (“we”, “us”, “our”) as data controller and processor
will collect and process any personal data in the course of operating the Service under
either your service agreements, as the case may be, (“Customer Agreement”) of
which this Privacy Policy forms part. Capitalised terms not otherwise defined in this
Privacy Policy shall have the meaning given to them in your Customer Agreement.
2. The information we collect
The personal data we hold about you is given directly by you and by people or
companies authorised by you to act on your behalf, and it may also include information
obtained from those third parties authorised by you to share such information with us,
including:
(a)       Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Service, posting User
          Content or requesting further services or reporting a problem;
(b)       Name, addresses, date of birth, gender and contact details;
(c)       Payment details (e.g. account number, sort code; payment card number,
          validity/expiry date, issue number and CVV number);
(d)       Any other data or information that we or any of our suppliers must request from
          you in order to perform our service;

(e)       Information about your financial interests or financial position;
(f)       Your contact details, including your e-mail address, home address and telephone
          numbers;
(g)       copies of passports or other identification evidence that you provide for anti-
          money laundering and anti-fraud purposes;
(h)       Records of telephone calls and any correspondence between you and us;
(i)       Information that you provide by filling in our surveys;
(j)       Details of your visits to the Service and the resources that you access (see also
          our Cookie Policy);
(k)       Internet protocol address, timezone/region, browser type/language, operating
          system, internet service provider, system details/settings;
(l)       Information about activities you undertake, such as the pages you visit,
          searches you make or marketing or links you click;
(m)       Transaction Data: retailers used, items purchased, value of transactions;
(n)       Credit checks to assess creditworthiness of your Business.
We aim to keep your personal data up-to-date, so please advise us of any changes by
updating your Account or e-mailing insert email address. You must notify us within thirty
days of any change in your name, residential address, contact details, identification
evidence given to us and any other details that we reasonably consider to be material to
our dealings with you in relation to the Service. We rely on you providing accurate
information to enable us to exercise our rights and comply with our obligations under
this Privacy Policy and cannot be held responsible if you providing incorrect information
in relation to age, for example.
Some of the information that we collect about you may include special categories of
personal data (such as information about racial or ethnic origin, criminal or alleged
criminal offences). We will usually seek separate permission from you in writing to
process these special categories of personal data.
If you fail to provide us with this information, or you object to us processing such
information the consequences are that we may be prevented from conducting business
with you, or continuing to manage your account(s) with us and we may be unable to
provide our services to you.

Use of Personal Information
We act as data controller and processor when processing and storing your personal data.
We may use information held about you in one or more of the following ways:
(a)      To ensure that content on the Service is presented in the most effective manner
         for you and for your computer or other devices for which we support access;
(b)      To provide you with information, products or services that you request or which
         we decide may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such
         purposes;
(c)      For statistical analysis;
(d)      To develop and improve the Service;
(e)      To update our records;
(f)      To identify which elements of the Service or other products might interest you;
(g)      To assess creditworthiness in accordance with the provisions of the applicable
         Customer Agreement;
(h)      To identify, prevent, detect or tackle fraud, money laundering and other crime;
(i)      To carry out checks required by applicable regulation or regulatory guidance;
(j)      To keep you informed about the Service and/or Transactions;
(k)      To carry out our obligations arising from and exercise our rights under, any
         agreements between you and either of us or other users of the Service;
(l)      To allow you to participate in interactive features of the Service, when you
         choose to do so;
(m)      To give you any notices under your Customer Agreement;
(n)      To administer your account;
(o)      To enforce Customer Agreements;
(p)      To promote the Service.
Lawful grounds
We have described the purposes for which we may use information about you. We are
permitted to process such information in this way, in compliance with the Data
Protection Legislation, by relying on one or more of the following lawful grounds:
(a)      you have explicitly agreed to us processing such information for a specific
         reason;

(b)       the processing is necessary to perform the agreement we have with you or to
          take steps to enter into an agreement with you;
(c)       the processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation we have; or
(d)       the processing is necessary for the purposes of a legitimate interest pursued by
          us, which might be:
                           (i)        to ensure that our Customer Accounts are well-
                                    managed;
                           (ii)       to provide our Service;
                           (iii)      to prevent fraud;
                           (iv)       to protect our business interests;
                           (v)        to ensure that complaints are investigated;
                           (vi)       to evaluate, develop or improve our products and
                                    services; or
                           (vii)      to keep our Customers informed about relevant
                                    products and services, unless you have indicated at
                                    any time that you do not wish us to do so.
In relation to any processing of special categories of personal data, we will generally rely
on obtaining specific consent in order to process such information, although it may be
necessary for us to use certain information in order to comply with our legal obligations
as a regulated entity (such as in relation to an alleged offence). Where you have
consented to our processing of such information (including special categories of personal
data) you may withdraw such consent at any time. Please note, however, that in certain
circumstances it may be still lawful for us to continue processing this information even
where consent has been withdrawn, if one of the other legal bases described above is
applicable.
Automated processing
When we use your information, we may use automated processes.
In particular, in order to comply with our obligations under anti-money laundering
legislation, we are required to verify the identity of all clients and other information
(including but not limited to details of any nationality, citizenship or rights of residence
you hold) to satisfy our regulatory obligations. We may do this using an electronic
verification system that we consider suitable or by asking you for documentary evidence.
If you want to know more about your rights in relation to automated decision making,
please contact us.

3. Sharing your personal data
We will keep your personal data confidential and only disclose it to others for the
purposes explained when you applied to open an account. We will ensure that if we
share such information with third parties, any such disclosure is at all times in
compliance with Data Protection Legislation. We may share your personal data:
(a)      In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case it may
         disclose your Personal Data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business
         or assets;
(b)      If substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case
         Personal Data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred
         assets;
(c)      If we are under a duty to disclose or share your Personal Data in order to
         comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply any agreements
         to which you are a party; or to protect our rights, property, or safety, or that of
         our customers, or others (which includes exchanging information with other
         companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk
         reduction);
(d)      If you request us, or give your permission for us to do so;
(e)      To a credit reference agency to check your identity and to prevent fraud, (it will
         also keep a record of your request and use it whenever anyone applies to be
         authenticated in your name);
(f)      To tell credit reference agencies that you have an account and how you run that
         account;
(g)      To our suppliers, agents and subcontractors to use for the purpose of operating
         the Service, under an obligation to take appropriate technical and organisational
         security measures against the unauthorised or unlawful processing of personal
         data and against the accidental loss or destruction of, or damage to, such
         personal data;
(h)      To investigate, prevent or detect fraud or carry out checks against money
         laundering;
(i)      To organisations providing a centralised application matching service which they
         collect from and about credit applications, for the purpose of preventing and
         detecting fraud;
(j)      For audit purposes and to meet obligations to any relevant regulatory authority
         or taxing authority.
We will also check your details with a fraud prevention agency/agencies and if you give
false or inaccurate information and we identify fraud, this will be recorded and we and

other organisations, including law enforcement agencies and debt collection agencies,
may access, use and search these records to:
(a)      help make decisions about credit and credit related services, for you and
         members of your household;
(b)      help make decisions on motor, household, credit, life and other insurance
         proposals and insurance claims, for you and members of your household;
(c)      trace debtors, recover debt, prevent fraud, and to manage your accounts or
         insurance policies;
(d)      prevent fraud and money laundering, for example, when:
         o        Checking details on applications for credit and credit related or other
                  facilities;
         o        Managing credit and credit related accounts or facilities;
         o        Checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; and
         o        Checking details of job applicants and employees.
Please contact us if you want to receive details of the relevant fraud prevention
agencies.
Sharing Third Party Information With Us
If any information which you provide to us relates to any third party (such as a joint
account holder) (a "Relevant Third Party"), by providing us with such information you
confirm that you are permitted to give us this information on their behalf.
Transferring Your Information Outside The UK
Our in data storage facilities are located within the European Union. However we do
store and process personal data outside the European Union and so information about
you in our possession may be transferred to other countries (which may include
countries outside the European Economic Area) for any of the purposes described in this
Privacy Policy, including our transmission of such information to our agents outside the
European Economic Area. If any such information (including special categories of
personal data) belongs to any Relevant Third Parties, by providing us with such
information you confirm that you have obtained any necessary permissions from such
persons to the reasonable use of their information for such purposes in accordance with
the following provisions, or are otherwise permitted to give us this information on their
behalf.

You and they understand and accept that these countries may have differing (and
potentially less stringent) laws relating to the degree of confidentiality afforded to the
information it holds and that such information can become subject to the laws and
disclosure requirements of such countries, including disclosure to governmental bodies,
regulatory agencies and private persons, as a result of applicable governmental or
regulatory inquiry, court order or other similar process. In addition, a number of
countries have agreements with other countries providing for exchange of information
for law enforcement, tax and other purposes.
When we, or our permitted third parties, transfer information outside the European
Economic Area, we or they will impose contractual obligations on the recipients of that
data to protect such information to the standard required in the European Economic
Area. We or they may require the recipient to subscribe to international frameworks
intended to enable secure data sharing.      In the case of transfers by us, we may also
transfer your information where:
(a)      the transfer is to a country deemed to provide adequate protection of your
         information by the European Commission; or
(b)      you have consented to the transfer.
If we transfer your information outside the European Economic Area in other
circumstances (for example because we have to provide such information by law), we
will use best endeavours to put in place appropriate safeguards to ensure that your
information remains adequately protected.
4. Your rights
You and Relevant Third Parties have a number of rights concerning the way that we use
your information. You are responsible for ensuring that Relevant Third Parties are aware
of these rights. At any time, you and they shall have the right:
(a)      to be informed about the processing of their personal data (i.e. for what
         purposes, what types, to what recipients it is disclosed, storage periods, any
         third party sources from which it was obtained, confirmation of whether we
         undertake automated decision-making, including profiling, and the logic,
         significance and envisaged consequences);
(b)      to request access to, or a copy of, any personal data we hold about them;
(c)      to request the rectification of their personal data, if they consider that it is
         inaccurate.;
(d)      to request the erasure of their personal data, if they consider that we do not
         have the right to hold it;

(e)      to object to their personal data being processed for a particular purpose or to
         request that we stop using their information;
(f)      to request not to be subject to a decision based on automated processing and to
         have safeguards put in place if they are being profiled based on their personal
         data;
(g)      to ask us to transfer a copy of their personal data to themselves or to another
         service provider or third party where technically feasible and otherwise required
         by [applicable regulations];
(h)      to withdraw, at any time, any consent that they have previously given to us for
         our use of their personal data; or
(i)      to ask us to stop or start sending them marketing messages at any time.
Access to Your Information
You and Relevant Third Parties may have a right of access to some, or all, of the
information we hold about you or them, or to have any inaccurate information corrected,
under the Data Protection Legislation. Any request for access to or a copy of your
personal data must be in writing and we will endeavour to respond within a reasonable
period and in any event within one month in compliance with Data Protection Legislation.
We will comply with our legal obligations as regards any individual’s rights as a data
subject.
We aim to ensure that the information we hold about you and Relevant Third Parties is
accurate at all times. To assist us in ensuring that such information is up to date, please
let us know if the personal details of you and Relevant Third Parties change by
contacting us We will correct any incorrect or incomplete information and will stop
processing personal data, or erase it, where there is no legal reason for us to continue to
hold or use that information.
5. Retaining Your Information
We will only keep the information we collect about you and Relevant Third Parties on our
systems or with third parties for as long as required for the purposes set out above or as
required to comply with any legal obligations to which we are subject. This will involve us
regularly reviewing our files to check that information is accurate and up-to-date and still
required.
If you close an account(s) you have with us, we decline your application to open an
account(s), or you decide not to go ahead with opening an account(s), we may still keep
your information. We may also continue to collect information from credit reference
agencies to use after you close your account(s) with us.

We will normally destroy or erase data after 5 years from the end of our agreement with
you or as required by any applicable regulations. However, we may retain your
information, or information relating to Relevant Third Party after you cease to be a client
for longer than this, provided it is necessary for a legal, regulatory, fraud prevention or
other legitimate business purpose.
6. Sending You Marketing Information
We may use your information from time to time to inform you and Relevant Third Parties
by letter, telephone, text (or similar) messages, email or other electronic means, about
similar products and services (including those of third parties) which may be of interest
to you or them. You are responsible for ensuring that those individuals are aware that
we may use their information for marketing purposes to inform them about services
which may be of interest to them.
You and Relevant Third Parties, at any time, request that we cease or do not send such
information by one, some or all channels, by contacting us.
7. Contacting Us
If you or a Relevant Third Party wish to exercise any of the rights relating to your
information set out above, or if you have any questions or comments about data
protection, or you wish to raise a complaint about how we are using your information
you can contact us using the following details, or any other details notified to you from
time to time:
(a)      Write    to    the   registered    and   head     office    of     Paymaster24  at
         privacy@paymaster24.com
(b)      Call +44 (0) 1223 967 376. Please note calls may be recorded or monitored for
         training purposes.
If you or a Relevant Third Party have any concerns about our use of your or their
information, you and they also have the right to make a complaint to the relevant Data
Protection    Authority   http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-
authorities/index_en.htm which regulate and supervise the use of personal data in the
EEA.
We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we do, we will post any changes
we    make    on   this  page   and   notify  you   via   email   or    via   your Account.
The Service may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of other
businesses, including networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of

these websites, please note that those third parties have their own privacy policies and
that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for those policies. Please check those
policies before you submit any personal data directly via those websites or to those third
parties.
